one of my favorite things about working
关于工作，我最喜欢的事情之一
with vectors is having the ability to
向量是有能力的
make complex designs out of simple
让复杂的设计变得简单
shapes a good example of such would be
形状就是这样的一个很好的例子
this iconic leaf design that was made
这个标志性的叶子设计是由
using only two circles a square and a
仅使用两个圆一个正方形和一个
little bit of design magic in today's
在今天的设计魔术中
lesson i'll be showing you how
我会教你怎么做
so getting us started here the first
所以让我们第一次从这里开始
thing we're going to do is draw our
我们要做的就是抽出我们的
circle so i'm going to locate the
圈，所以我要找到
circles and ellipses tool which is
圆和椭圆工具，它是
located over here
位于这里
and then i'm going to click and drag on
然后我会点击并拖拽
the canvas while holding down the
按住画布的同时
control key so we get a nice perfectly
Ctrl键，这样我们就可以得到一个完美的
round circle like that
像这样的圆形
now what i'm going to do is open up the
现在我要做的是打开
fill and stroke menu which is located
位于的填充和描边菜单
over here or you can press ctrl shift
在这里，或者你可以按ctrl Shift键
and f to open that up and it should open
把它打开，它应该会打开
up on the right hand side of your screen
在屏幕的右手边
over here now you can use these sliders
在这里，现在您可以使用这些滑块
to make this whatever color you'd like
把它做成你喜欢的任何颜色
i'm going to make my leaf green so i'm
我要让我的叶子变绿，所以我
going to use a green shade over here
我要用这边的绿色遮阳板
[Music]
[音乐]
there we go
好了，我们走吧
and what i'm going to do now is reduce
我现在要做的是减少
the opacity of this circle i want to
这个圈子的不透明，我想
drop this down roughly in half because
把这个降到一半是因为
it's important that we're going to see
重要的是我们要看到
through the shapes that we're about to
通过我们即将看到的形状
work with
与.一起工作
once you've done that you can go back to
完成后，您可以返回到
the select tool over here and what i
这里的选择工具和我
want to do is right click on this object
想要做的就是右键单击此对象
and go to duplicate now we have two
现在我们有两个
copies of it
复印件
so now i'm going to hold down my control
所以现在我要控制住我的控制
key and click and drag this shape down
键并单击并向下拖动此形状
here so that we have this intersecting
在这里，我们有这个交叉点
area between these two circles right
这两个圆之间的区域右侧
here which is going to represent our
这将代表我们的
leaf shape so now i'm going to create a
树叶的形状，所以现在我要创建一个
new object out of these intersecting
这些相交中的新物体
areas by clicking and dragging over both
通过在两个区域上单击并拖动
of them we want to make sure we have
我们想要确保我们有
both of them selected and then go to
选择这两个选项，然后转到
path and select intersection
路径和选择交点
and this is going to represent part of
这将代表着
our leaf anyway
不管怎样，我们的叶子
so now we're going to create this stem
所以现在我们要创建这个茎
i'm going to put this off to the side
我要把这个放在一边
for now i'm going to use a couple of
现在，我将使用几个
squares to make this stem i'm going to
方块来做这个茎，我要
grab the squares and rectangles tool
抓取正方形和矩形工具
which is over here
它就在这里
click and drag on the canvas to create
在画布上单击并拖动以创建
your shape hold down control to lock the
您的形状按住Ctrl以锁定
aspect ratio so we get a nice
纵横比，所以我们得到一个很好的
symmetrical square like that
像这样对称的正方形
and now what we want to do is first make
现在我们要做的是首先让
sure that the corners of the square are
当然，广场的每个角落都是
sharp up here in the toolbar this icon
在工具栏上锐化此处的此图标
right here that reads make corners sharp
就在这里，阅读让角落变得尖锐
when you hover your cursor over it if
当您将光标悬停在它上面时
it's grayed out then that means your
它是灰色的，这意味着你的
corners are already sharp and you're
拐角已经很锋利了，而你
good to go if you have rounded corners
如果你有圆角，就可以走了
go ahead and click that button and it'll
继续点击那个按钮，它就会
make your corner sharp
让你的角落变得锋利
okay so let's convert this to a path now
好的，现在让我们将其转换为路径
let's go to path and select object to
让我们转到路径并选择要
path
路径
and now we can grab the nodes tool which
现在我们可以获取Nodes工具，该工具
is right here and i'm going to click and
就在这里，我要点击并
drag over this node right here to select
将鼠标拖到此节点上以选择
it and i'm going to press delete on the
它和我将按Delete键
keyboard to get rid of that node
键盘去掉那个节点
and then i'm going to click and drag
然后我要点击并拖动
over the remaining three nodes and make
在剩下的三个节点上，并使
them sharp by clicking on this button up
点击这个按钮就可以让他们锐利起来
here that says make selected nodes
此处显示的是创建选定的节点
corner
拐角
and now we have this triangle shape like
现在我们有这个三角形，就像
that
那
so let's go back to our select tool
那么让我们回到我们的选择工具
let's give this a different color so we
让我们给它换一种颜色，这样我们
can differentiate it from the leaf when
可以将它与树叶区分开来
we apply it over i'm going to make this
我们把它涂在上面，我要做这个
red
红色
and i'm going to right click this and go
我要用鼠标右键点击它，然后开始
to duplicate
复制
and i'm going to make this one a
我要把这件事做成一个
different color i'll make this one blue
不同的颜色，我要把这件改成蓝色
and then i'll come up here where it says
然后我会走到这里，上面写着
flip selected objects vertically i'll do
垂直翻转选定的对象，我来做
that so it's flipped vertically and i'm
所以它是垂直翻转的，我
going to hold ctrl and move this one
按住Ctrl键并移动这一个
down here like that now we want this to
像这样下去，现在我们希望这件事
attach to this right here so i'm going
就贴在这里，所以我要去
to temporarily turn on snapping which is
临时打开捕捉，这是
this little magnet icon up here in the
这个小小的磁铁图标在这里
top right corner and then you should be
右上角，然后你应该是
able to just click and drag and snap it
只需点击、拖动和捕捉即可
in place like that and then we also want
在这样的地方，然后我们也想
to flip this horizontally so come over
要水平翻转，所以过来
here where it says flip selected objects
此处显示翻转选定对象
horizontally and select that this is
水平方向，并选择这是
what we're looking for right here
我们现在要找的就是
so let's turn off snapping now
现在，让我们关闭捕捉
actually no you know what let's leave
实际上，不，你知道什么，我们走吧
that on for now i'm going to click and
现在我要点击并打开它
drag over both of these objects
将鼠标拖到这两个对象上
i'm going to group them together by
我将按以下顺序将它们组合在一起
going to object
我要表示反对
and selecting
和选择
[Music]
[音乐]
and then i'm just going to take this
然后我要拿着这个
bottom node right here or this bottom
底部节点就在这里或这个底部
handle and just bring this up so that we
把这件事提出来，这样我们就
end up with a shape like this so we have
最后得到这样的形状，所以我们有
these two triangles these two long
这两个三角形这两个长
triangles going this way
三角形往这边走
and now i'm going to take my leaf let me
现在我要带上我的叶子让我
bring this over here let me make this a
把这个拿过来，让我把它弄成
little bigger i'm going to hold ctrl and
再大一点，我要按住Ctrl键，然后
i'm going to click and drag this scaling
我要单击并拖动此缩放
handle right here
把手就在这里
to scale that up
要扩大规模，
and i want to take the corners this
我想拿下这个角落
corner of this object right here and
这个物体的一角就在这里
snap it
抓拍它
into this corner right here just like
就在这个角落里，就像
that and now we can turn off our
现在我们可以关闭我们的
snapping because if we leave that
抓拍是因为如果我们把它留下
enabled any further it's just going to
如果再进一步启用，它只会
get in our way
挡住我们的路
so now we have our stem in place i'm
所以现在我们已经就位了，我是
just going to hold ctrl and move this
只需按住Ctrl键并移动它
over like this
像这样翻过去
i might even make this a little more a
我甚至可能会让这件事更像是
little longer like that
再长一点，就像这样
and what's how this works is this red
它的工作原理是这个红色的
object is going to represent the stem
对象将表示词干
and this blue object is actually going
这个蓝色的物体实际上是在
to be used as negative space for this
将用作此的负值空间
leaf let me show you what i mean here
利夫，让我告诉你我的意思
let's ungroup this object let's go to
让我们解开这个对象，让我们转到
object and select
对象并选择
ungroup and then click off of the
取消分组，然后从
graphic to deselect everything i'm going
取消选择我要去的所有内容的图形
to select just this blue shape right
要选择正确的蓝色形状
here and then i'm going to hold shift
我要时不时地换班
and click on the green leaf right there
然后点击那里的绿叶
so we have both of them selected and i'm
所以我们两个都被选中了，我是
going to subtract those two shapes from
从这两个形状中减去
each other by going to path
通过走到PATH来彼此
difference
差异
and now we end up with something like
现在我们得到了类似这样的结果
that right there
就在那里
so let's click and drag over everything
所以，让我们点击并拖动所有内容
here both of those objects and go to
这两个对象都在这里，然后转到
path
路径
union and now we have our base shape for
现在我们有了我们的基本形状
the leaf in fact we can take the opacity
事实上，我们可以把树叶的不透明度
of this and bring this back up and i'm
再提起这件事，我就会
going to scale this down i'm going to
为了缩小规模，我要
hold ctrl and to lock the proportions
按住Ctrl键并锁定比例
and scale that down like that so we have
像这样缩小规模，所以我们有
a rudimentary leaf here we're going to
这是一片原始的树叶，我们将在这里
make this look a little more whimsical
让这看起来有点异想天开
and and with curved edges uh by using
并用弯曲的边缘呃通过使用
the pen tool so let me uh right click on
钢笔工具，让我，呃，右击
this and go to copy
这个，然后去复制
or the pencil tool router come over here
或者铅笔工具路由器到这里来
to the pencil tool or the draw free hand
到铅笔工具或徒手绘画
lines tool you can use the letter p on
线工具您可以在上面使用字母p
your keyboard to access that
你的键盘来访问它
and up here where it says shape in the
在这上面写着形状在
tool setting we want to change that to
刀具设置我们想要将其更改为
from clipboard
从剪贴板
and the smoothing up here this is
而这里的平滑效果是
important as well this is based on this
同样重要的是，这是基于这一点
will vary based on your screen
将根据您的屏幕而不同
resolution but i'm going to start out
决心，但我要开始了
with 60 and see how that looks
60美元，看看这是什么样子
and now what i'm going to do is i'm just
现在我要做的是我只是
going to click and drag like this to
要像这样点击并拖动
create
创建
a line like that and if you notice it
像这样的台词，如果你注意到了
took that strap that it took that uh
拿着那个皮带，拿着那个，呃
shape and stretched it out along that
塑造并沿着那个方向伸展
path
路径
now the problem here is that the the
现在这里的问题是
leaf is way too thin so let's come over
树叶太薄了，我们过来吧
here to the edit pads my nodes tool
此处为编辑板我的结点工具
and there should be some little there
而且那里应该有一些
should be a little handle right here
这里应该有个小把手
that you could just pull out like this
你可以像这样抽出
and it increases
而且它增加了
the size of your leaf as you can see
你能看到的树叶的大小
here
这里
and this right here is the effect we're
这就是我们正在产生的效果
going for
去找
so let me make this green
所以让我把它变成绿色的
let me remove the stroke by holding
让我通过按住来移除笔划
shift and clicking on the red x over
按住Shift键并单击红色的x
here
这里
and now i'm going to grab my selection
现在我要拿出我的选择
tool and scale this down to size a
工具，并将其缩小到一个
little more a little more of a normal
再多一点，再正常一点
size like that
像这样的大小
and now what i'm going to do is i'm
现在我要做的是
going to finalize this by converting it
我将通过转换它来最终确定它
to a path i'll go to path
去一条我要去的小路
and select object to path
并选择要进行路径的对象
and we have a little bit of a whimsical
我们有一点异想天开
leaf here now the problem is i'm not too
现在的问题是我不是太
happy with how these lines look they
对这些线条看起来很满意
don't look as fluid as they could be so
不要看起来像他们可能会变得那么流畅
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
我要做的是我要
manually adjust them let me zoom in on
手动调整它们，让我放大
this by holding ctrl and rolling up the
这是通过按住Ctrl键并将
mouse wheel
鼠标滚轮
i'm going to grab my edit paths by nodes
我将按节点获取我的编辑路径
tool i'm going to click on this object
工具，我要点击这个对象
to select it and if you see all of these
选择它，如果您看到所有这些
little nodes here going along this edge
这里的小节点沿着这条边走
i'm going to select all of those nodes
我将选择所有这些节点
i'm going to hold shift while doing this
我要在做这个的时候按住Shift键
to make sure i can select multiple nodes
以确保我可以选择多个节点
at a time and we want to have only these
我们想要的只有这些
nodes selected up here and then just
在此处选择的节点，然后
press delete on the keyboard to get rid
按键盘上的Delete键可以删除
of them and now you should have these
现在你应该拥有这些
two handles that you can adjust
两个可以调整的手柄
according to your preference so i want
根据您的喜好，所以我想
to give this more of a fluid contour
为了给这个更流畅的轮廓
like that that looks a lot better so i'm
像这样看起来好多了，所以我
going to do the same thing down here now
现在也要在这里做同样的事情
i'm going to start selecting these nodes
我将开始选择这些节点
while holding shift on my keyboard so i
同时按住键盘上的Shift键，所以我
can select multiple nodes at a time
一次可以选择多个节点
and then press delete on the keyboard to
然后按键盘上的Delete键以
get rid of them
除掉他们
and now i can take this handle and
现在我可以拿着这个把手
manually shape it
手动调整形状
however i please
我怎么想都行
[Music]
[音乐]
okay there we go that looks a lot better
好的，我们走吧，看起来好多了
so let me grab the selection tool i'm
所以让我拿起选择工具
gonna press one on the keyboard to zoom
我要按键盘上的一键进行缩放
back out to a hundred percent and there
回到100%，然后就在那里
you go now we have one of our leaves
你走吧，我们有一片树叶
okay so let me show you another way you
好的，让我带你看看另一种方式
can do this or actually let me just show
可以做到这一点，或者让我展示一下
you how to make another leaf of another
你如何让另一片叶子变成另一片叶子
uh style
呃风格
instead of drawing the curved line like
而不是像这样画曲线
it did before i'm going to draw like a
在我要画画之前就是这样
u-shaped line so i should still have
U字形的线条，所以我应该还是
this copied to my clipboard we do have
这是复制到我的剪贴板上的我们有
the settings in place here from
此处的设置来自
clipboard i'm just going to click and
剪贴板我只需点击和
drag to create like a smiley face like
拖动可创建类似如下的笑脸
that
那
okay that didn't come out as expected
好的，这并不像预期的那样
that looks really sloppy right there so
这看起来真的很马虎，所以
i'm going to press ctrl z to undo that
我要按Ctrl z键来撤消该操作
i'm going to increase the smoothing up
我要加大打磨的力度
to 70.
到70岁。
and try that again
然后再试一次
[Music]
[音乐]
okay that looks a little better that
好的，这样看起来好一点。
that's not that's still not what i'm
不是这样的，我现在也不是这样的
looking for but that's enough for me to
寻找，但这对我来说已经足够了
work with so i'm going to leave it as it
所以我要让它保持原样
is let me grab my selection tool let me
是让我拿起我的选择工具让我
scale this down like that i'm going to
像这样缩小规模，我要
hold ctrl and shift while scaling so i
按住Ctrl键和Shift键进行缩放，以便
could scale from the center and preserve
可以从中心扩展并保存
the proportions
比例
and i'm going to make this green
我要把它变成绿色的
i'll remove the stroke by holding shift
我将通过按住Shift键来删除笔划
and clicking the x
并单击x
and i will go to path
我会走到小路上
object to path
对象到路径
and now i can go to my edit pads by
现在我可以通过以下方式进入我的编辑键盘
nodes tool and let me zoom in and clean
Nodes工具，让我可以放大和清理
this up a little bit
这个稍微涨了一点
press the delete key to get rid of those
按Delete键可删除这些文件
nodes just like we did before same
节点，就像我们之前做的一样
process
制程
take this handle and
拿着这个把手
take this handle and bring that in a
拿着这个把手，把那个放进一个
little bit
一点点
[Music]
[音乐]
there we go
好了，我们走吧
and then i will take these handle take
然后我要拿着这些把手
these nodes down here and get rid of
这些节点在这里，并摆脱
them
他们
just like i did before just to make this
就像我以前做的那样，只是为了做这个
more smooth i missed one right there let
更流畅，我错过了一个就在那里，让
me get rid of that one there we go
我处理掉那个，我们走吧
so let me adjust this handle
所以让我调整一下这个把手
and i think this one looks pretty good
我觉得这件看起来很不错
yeah that's good enough and once you're
是的，这已经足够好了，一旦你
done you can grab the selection tool
完成后，您可以抓起选择工具
zoom out to 100
缩小到100
by pressing one on the keyboard and
按下键盘上的一个键，然后
there we go now we have another leaf
我们走了，现在我们有了另一片叶子
and there you go you should get the idea
就这样，你应该明白了
you can draw all of these different
你可以画出所有这些不同的
whimsical style leaves by grabbing your
异想天开的风格通过抓住你的
pencil tool over here and drawing
铅笔工具在这里画画
different contours as you can see there
你可以在那里看到不同的轮廓
like that or maybe not maybe not as
就像那样，或许不是，也许不是
sloppy but you get the idea
草率，但你明白我的意思
okay
好吧
so there we go let me take this one
所以我们走吧，让我来拿这个
scale this down
缩小规模
[Music]
[音乐]
and there we go there is another leaf
我们走到那里，又多了一片叶子
okay so now we have all of these
好的，现在我们有了所有这些
different leaves and different shapes
不同的叶子和不同的形状
going in different directions and
往不同的方向走，
different contours and you could
不同的轮廓，你可以
actually arrange these to make somewhat
其实把这些整理一下就可以了
of a pattern or you can use these for
或者您可以将这些用于
logos or icons or whatever else you'd
徽标或图标或其他任何你想要的东西
like
喜欢
so i think that should do it for this
所以我认为这应该可以解决这个问题
tutorial that is how you can draw simple
这就是如何简单地绘制教程
iconic leaves using inkscape before i
图标树叶在我之前使用Inkscape
end this video if you found this lesson
如果您发现此课程，请结束此视频
useful then consider checking out my
有用的，那么可以考虑查看我的
inkscape master class it's a collection
Inkscape大师类，它是一个集合
of over 60 videos where i go over all of
60多个视频中，我浏览了所有
the tools and features in inkscape and i
Inkscape和I中的工具和功能
explain what they are and demonstrate
解释它们是什么并演示它们
how they work kind of like how i did in
它们的工作原理有点像我在
this video we even have a private
这个视频我们甚至有一个私人的
community where you can ask questions
您可以提出问题的社区
and get help from me anytime you want
只要你愿意，随时向我寻求帮助
and best of all there's no monthly
最棒的是没有月刊
membership fees you just pay 17 one time
会员费你只需一次性付17英镑
and you're in for life i'll have some
你要终身监禁，我要喝一些
information about that in the
有关这方面的信息，请参阅
description of the video if you want to
视频描述(如果您想要
check that out as always thanks for
一如既往地查看，谢谢
watching
观看
[Music]
[音乐]